{
    "Exam2": {
        "Q4b.tex": [
            {
                "question": "If $A$ is $2 \\times 3$ and is in RREF, and $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&3&-1\\end{pmatrix}^T$ spans $\\Null A$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 & a_3 \\\\ a_4 & a_5 & a_6 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n    $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_5 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_6 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $x$ spans $\\Null A$ then $A$ has two pivots. Since $A$ must also be in RREF we can set $a_1=a_5=1$ and $a_2=a_4 = 0$. So far we have\n    $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}$$\n    But $A\\vec x = \\vec 0$, so \n    \\begin{align}\n        A\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\3\\\\-1\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 2-a_3 \\\\3-a_6 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    So $a_3 = 2$ and $a_6 = 3$. Listing all of the values:\n    \\begin{align}\n        a_1 = 1, a_2 = 0, a_3 = 2, a_4=0, a_5 = 1, a_6 = 3\n    \\end{align}\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "If $A$ is $2 \\times 3$ and is in RREF, and $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&4&-2\\end{pmatrix}^T$ spans $\\Null A$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 & a_3 \\\\ a_4 & a_5 & a_6 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n    $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_5 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_6 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $x$ spans $\\Null A$ then $A$ has two pivots. Since $A$ must also be in RREF we can set $a_1=a_5=1$ and $a_2=a_4 = 0$. So far we have\n    $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}$$\n    But $A\\vec x = \\vec 0$, so \n    \\begin{align}\n        A\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\4\\\\-2\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 1-2a_3 \\\\4-2a_6 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    So $a_3 = 2$ and $a_6 = 3$. Listing all of the values:\n    \\begin{align}\n        a_1 = 1, a_2 = 0, a_3 = 1/2, a_4=0, a_5 = 1, a_6 = 2\n    \\end{align}\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "If $A$ is $2 \\times 3$ and is in RREF, and $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 6&-1&2\\end{pmatrix}^T$ spans $\\Null A$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 & a_3 \\\\ a_4 & a_5 & a_6 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n    $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_5 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_6 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $x$ spans $\\Null A$ then $A$ has two pivots. Since $A$ must also be in RREF we can set $a_1=a_5=1$ and $a_2=a_4 = 0$. So far we have\n    $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}$$\n    But $A\\vec x = \\vec 0$, so \n    \\begin{align}\n        A\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 6\\\\-1\\\\2\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 6+2a_3 \\\\-1+2a_6 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    So $a_3 = -3$ and $a_6 = 1/2$. Listing all of the values:\n    \\begin{align}\n        a_1 = 1, a_2 = 0, a_3 = -3, a_4=0, a_5 = 1, a_6 = 1/2\n    \\end{align}\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "If $A$ is $2 \\times 3$ and is in RREF, and $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 3&-1&7\\end{pmatrix}^T$ spans $\\Null A$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 & a_3 \\\\ a_4 & a_5 & a_6 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n    $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_5 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_6 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $x$ spans $\\Null A$ then $A$ has two pivots. Since $A$ must also be in RREF we can set $a_1=a_5=1$ and $a_2=a_4 = 0$. So far we have\n    $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}$$\n    But $A\\vec x = \\vec 0$, so \n    \\begin{align}\n        A\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 3\\\\-1\\\\7\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 3+7a_3 \\\\-1+7a_6 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    So $a_3 = -3/7$ and $a_6 = 1/7$. Listing all of the values:\n    \\begin{align}\n        a_1 = 1, a_2 = 0, a_3 = -3/7, a_4=0, a_5 = 1, a_6 = 1/7\n    \\end{align}\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "If $A$ is $3 \\times 2$ and is in RREF, and $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 3&-1\\end{pmatrix}^T$ spans $\\Null A$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\\\ a_5 & a_6 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n    $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_5 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_6 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $\\vec x$ spans the null space then $\\Dim(\\Null(A))=1$, so there must be exactly one pivot in our matrix that has two columns. And the second column of $A$ must be 3 times the first column so that $A\\vec x = \\vec 0$. So $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&3\\\\0&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}$$ is the only possible matrix. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "If $A$ is $2 \\times 3$ and is in RREF, and $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&-1&-1\\end{pmatrix}^T$ spans $\\Null A$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 & a_3 \\\\ a_4 & a_5 & a_6 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n    $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_5 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_6 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $x$ spans $\\Null A$ then $A$ has two pivots. Since $A$ must also be in RREF we can set $a_1=a_5=1$ and $a_2=a_4 = 0$. So far we have\n    $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}$$\n    But $A\\vec x = \\vec 0$, so \n    \\begin{align}\n        A\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\-1\\\\-1\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 2-a_3 \\\\-1-a_6 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    So $a_3 = 2$ and $a_6 = -1$. Listing all of the values:\n    \\begin{align}\n        a_1 = 1, a_2 = 0, a_3 = 2, a_4=0, a_5 = 1, a_6 = -1\n    \\end{align}\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "If $A$ is $2 \\times 3$, is in RREF, and $\\Null A = \\{ \\vec x\\in \\mathbb R^3 \\, | \\, x_1=x_3, x_2 = 0\\}$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 & a_3 \\\\ a_4 & a_5 & a_6 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n    $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.75cm}}$, \n    $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.75cm}}$, \n    $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.75cm}}$, \n    $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.75cm}}$,\n    $a_5 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.75cm}}$,\n    $a_6 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.75cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The nullspace of $A$ is one dimensional, so $A$ has two pivots. The nullspace is spanned by $(1,0,1)^T$, so \n  \\begin{equation}\n      \\begin{pmatrix}\n          1 & \\ast & \\ast \\\\ 0 & 1 & \\ast \n      \\end{pmatrix} \n      \\begin{pmatrix}\n          1 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 1 \n      \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix}\n          0 \\\\ 0 \n      \\end{pmatrix}\n  \\end{equation}\n But our matrix must be in RREF, so \n  \\begin{equation}\n      \\begin{pmatrix}\n          1 & 0 & \\ast \\\\ 0 & 1 & \\ast \n      \\end{pmatrix} \n      \\begin{pmatrix}\n          1 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 1 \n      \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix}\n          0 \\\\ 0 \n      \\end{pmatrix}\n  \\end{equation} \n  Then, you can see that  $A=\\begin{pmatrix}\n     1 & 0 & -1 \\\\ 0 & 1 & 0 \n \\end{pmatrix}$. This is the only possible answer. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "If $A$ is $2 \\times 3$ and is in RREF, and $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 4&1&-7\\end{pmatrix}^T$ spans $\\Null A$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 & a_3 \\\\ a_4 & a_5 & a_6 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n    $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_5 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,\n    $a_6 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Since $\\vec x$ spans $\\Null A$, $A$ has two pivots. Since $A$ must also be in RREF we can set $a_1=a_5=1$ and $a_2=a_4 = 0$. So far we have\n    $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}$$\n    But $A\\vec x = \\vec 0$, so \n    \\begin{align}\n        A\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_3\\\\0&1&a_6\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 4\\\\1\\\\-7\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 4-7a_3 \\\\1-7a_6 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \n    \\end{align}\n    So $a_3 = 4/7$ and $a_6 = 1/7$. Listing all of the values:\n    \\begin{align}\n        a_1 = 1, a_2 = 0, a_3 = 4/7, a_4=0, a_5 = 1, a_6 = 1/7\n    \\end{align}\n    } \n   \\else"
            }
        ],
        "Q6d.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part The dimension of the subspace $\\{\\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^4 \\, | \\, x_1-x_3 = 0\\}$ is $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The dimension is $3$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The dimension of the column space of $A=\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&1\\\\1&1&2\\end{pmatrix}$ is $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "By inspection the third column is the sum of the first two, and the first two columns are independent. So $A$ has two pivots, and the number of pivots is the rank, so $\\Rank A = 2$. Alternatively we could also row reduce the matrix and find that there are only two pivots, and so the rank must be two. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The dimension of the subspace $\\{\\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^6 \\, | \\, x_1-x_3 = 0, \\, x_2-x_4=0\\}$ is $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The dimension is $4$. Note we are told that \n    $$x_1 - x_3 = 0, \\ x_2-x_4 =0$$\n    But these conditions can be written as\n    $$x_1 = x_3 , \\ x_2 = x_4 $$\n    So vectors in the space have the form \n    $$ x \n    = \\begin{pmatrix} x_1 \\\\ x_2 \\\\ x_3 \\\\ x_4 \\\\ x_5 \\\\ x_6 \\end{pmatrix} \n    = \\begin{pmatrix} x_3 \\\\ x_4 \\\\ x_3 \\\\ x_4 \\\\ x_5 \\\\ x_6 \\end{pmatrix}\n    = x_3\\begin{pmatrix} 1 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 1 \\\\ 0\\\\ 0 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix} \n    + x_4\\begin{pmatrix}  0 \\\\ 1 \\\\ 0\\\\ 1 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    + x_5\\begin{pmatrix}  0 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 0\\\\ 0 \\\\ 1 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    + x_6\\begin{pmatrix}  0 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 0\\\\ 0 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 1 \\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    From our parametric vector form we see that the following set of vectors are in the subspace and are independent. \n    $$\n    \\left\\{\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 1 \\\\ 0\\\\ 0 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix}  0 \\\\ 1 \\\\ 0\\\\ 1 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix}  0 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 0\\\\ 0 \\\\ 1 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix}  0 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 0\\\\ 0 \\\\ 0 \\\\ 1 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\right\\}\n    $$\n    Note that each vector satisfies the given conditions because \n    \\begin{itemize}\n        \\item each vector is in $\\mathbb R^6$\n        \\item each vector satisfies $x_1 - x_3 = 0$\n        \\item each vector satisfies $x_2-x_4 =0$\n    \\end{itemize}\n    There are four vectors in this set, they are independent, and they span the set. The dimension of a space is the number of vectors needed to form a basis for it, so the dimension is 4. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part How many vectors are needed to form a basis for the subspace $\\{\\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^4 \\, | \\, x_1+x_2 = 0\\}$? $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "$3$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The dimension of the column space of $A=\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&1\\\\1&1&2\\end{pmatrix}$ is $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "By inspection the third column is the sum of the first two, and the first two columns are independent. So $A$ has two pivots, and the number of pivots is the rank, so $\\Rank A = 2$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part How many vectors are needed to form a basis for the subspace $\\{\\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^5 \\, | \\, x_1+x_2 = 0\\}$? $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "$4$. Vectors in the subspace have the general form \n    $$x \n    = \\begin{pmatrix} x_1\\\\x_2\\\\x_3\\\\x_4\\\\x_5\\end{pmatrix} \n    = \\begin{pmatrix} -x_2\\\\x_2\\\\x_3\\\\x_4\\\\x_5\\end{pmatrix}\n    =x_2\\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\1\\\\0\\\\0\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}\n    +x_3\\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\\\1\\\\0\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}\n    +x_4\\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\\\0\\\\1\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}\n    +x_5\\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\\\0\\\\0\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    There are 4 independent vectors in the basis for this subspace. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose $S$ is the subspace $S=\\{\\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^5 \\, | \\, x_1+x_2 = 0, x_3+x_4 = 0\\}$. How many vectors are needed to form a basis for $S$? $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "$S$ is determined by two linear conditions and vectors in $S$ live in $\\mathbb R^5$.  Hence, $S$ is three dimensional.  $x_1$ is free, but not $x_2$. $x_3$ is free, but not $x_4$, and then $x_5$ is free.  A general vector in $S$ is \n    \\begin{equation}\n        \\begin{pmatrix}\n            x_1 \\\\ - x_1 \\\\ x_3 \\\\ - x_3 \\\\ x_5 \n        \\end{pmatrix} = x_1 \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\-1\\\\0\\\\0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}+x_3\\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\0\\\\1\\\\-1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}+ x_5\\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\0\\\\0\\\\0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{equation}\n    There are 3 independent vectors in the basis for this subspace.     \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose $S$ is the subspace $S=\\{\\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^6 \\, | \\, x_1+x_2 = 0, x_3+2x_4 = 0\\}$. How many vectors are needed to form a basis for $S$? $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Vectors in $S$ have 6 entries and $S$ is determined by two linear conditions.  Hence, $S$ is four dimensional.  $x_1$ is free, but not $x_2$. $x_3$ is free, but not $x_4$, and then $x_5$ and $x_6$ are  free.  A general vector in $S$ is \n    \\begin{equation}\n        \\begin{pmatrix}\n            x_1 \\\\ - x_1 \\\\ x_3 \\\\ - x_3/2 \\\\ x_5 \\\\ x_6 \n        \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{equation}\n    The correct answer to this question is $4$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            }
        ],
        "Q6e.tex": [],
        "Q6c.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times2$, $\\Col A$ is the line $x_1=2x_2$, $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1=-x_2$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n        $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $\\Col A$ is the line $x_1=2x_2$ then a vector in $\\Col A$ is $\\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$ because if $x_2=1$, then $x_1=2$. Then the first column of $A$ can be $\\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$ or $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&c_1\\\\1&c_2\\end{pmatrix}$. We need to work out what $c_1$ and $c_2$ are, but if $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1+x_2=0$ then a vector in the null space of $A$ is $v = \\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$, so $$Av = \\begin{pmatrix}2&c_1\\\\1&c_2 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\1\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}$$ This gives us $c_1 = 2$, $c_2 = 1$, so $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&2\\\\1&1\\end{pmatrix}$, but any non-zero scalar multiple of this matrix also works. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times2$, $\\Col A$ is spanned by $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\2\\end{pmatrix}$, $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1=-x_2$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n        $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "A vector in $\\Col A$ is $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\2\\end{pmatrix}$. Then the first column of $A$ can be $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\2\\end{pmatrix}$ or $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&c_1\\\\2&c_2\\end{pmatrix}$. We need to work out what $c_1$ and $c_2$ are, but if $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1+x_2=0$ then a vector in the null space of $A$ is $v = \\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$, so $$Av = \\begin{pmatrix}1&c_1\\\\2&c_2 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\1\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}$$ This gives us $c_1 = 1$, $c_2 = 2$, so $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1\\\\2&2\\end{pmatrix}$, but any non-zero scalar multiple of this matrix also works. For example we could have also used any of the matrices below. \n    $$\\begin{pmatrix} 1&1\\\\2&2\\end{pmatrix} , \\begin{pmatrix} 2&2\\\\4&4\\end{pmatrix},\\begin{pmatrix} 10&10\\\\20&20\\end{pmatrix} , \\ldots $$\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If matrix $A$ is $2\\times2$, $\\Col A$ is the line $x_2 =0$ and $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1=-2x_2$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n        $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If the column space is the $x_1$-axis then matrix has the form $$A= \\begin{pmatrix} a&b\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}$$ \n    where $a$ and $b$ are real numbers. If $\\Nul A$ is the line $x_1=-2x_2$ then $\\begin{pmatrix}-2\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ is in the null space and $$\\begin{pmatrix} a&b\\\\0&0 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}-2\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}$$ So $-2a+b=0$, and we can choose $a=1$ and $b=2$. So we can set $$a_1=1, a_2 = 2, a_3 =0, a_4=0$$ There are other choices for $a_1, a_2$ that we can use but we must have that $a_3=a_4=0$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If matrix $A$ is $2\\times2$, $\\Col A$ is the line $x_2 =0$ and $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1=-2x_2$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n        $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If the column space is the $x_1$-axis then matrix has the form $$A= \\begin{pmatrix} a&b\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}$$ \n    where $a$ and $b$ are real numbers. If $\\Nul A$ is the line $x_1=-2x_2$ then $\\begin{pmatrix}-2\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ is in the null space and $$\\begin{pmatrix} a&b\\\\0&0 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}-2\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}$$ So $-2a+b=0$, and we can choose $a=1$ and $b=2$. So we can set $$a_1=1, a_2 = 2, a_3 =0, a_4=0$$ There are other choices for $a_1, a_2$ that we can use but we must have that $a_3=a_4=0$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times2$, $\\Col A$ is the line $x_1=8x_2$, $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1+4x_2=0$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ 1 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n    $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n    $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $\\Col A$ is the line $x_1=8x_2$ then a vector in $\\Col A$ is $\\begin{pmatrix} 8\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$ because if $x_2=1$, then $x_1=8$. Then the first column of $A$ can be $\\begin{pmatrix} 8\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$ or $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 8&c_1\\\\1&c_2\\end{pmatrix}$. We need to work out what $c_1$ and $c_2$ are, but if $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1+4x_2=0$ then a vector in the null space of $A$ is $v = \\begin{pmatrix} 4\\\\-1\\end{pmatrix}$. Because if $x_2=-1$, $x_1=4$. So $$Av = \\begin{pmatrix}8&c_1\\\\1&c_2 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 4\\\\-1\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}$$ This gives us $c_1 = 32$, $c_2 = 4$, so \n    $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 8&32\\\\1&4\\end{pmatrix}$$ We are forced to have the entry in the lower left be 1, so this is the only possible answer. \n\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If matrix $A$ is $2\\times2$, upper triangular, and $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1=-x_2$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & 1 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n        $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1=-x_2$ then a vector in $\\Nul A$ is $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\-1\\end{pmatrix}$. Then the first row of $A$ can be $\\begin{pmatrix} 1&1 \\end{pmatrix}$ so $A = \\begin{pmatrix}1&1\\\\c_1&c_2\\end{pmatrix}$. We need to work out what $c_1$ and $c_2$ are, but if $\\Null A$ is a line and $A$ is upper triangular, then $c_1=c_2=0$. This gives us\n    $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}$. This is the only possible answer. So $a_1=1$, $a_3=a_4=0$. \n\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If matrix $A$ is $2\\times2$, $\\Col A$ is the $x_1$-axis, and $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1=-2x_2$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} 1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n        $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If the column space is the $x_1$-axis then matrix has the form $$A= \\begin{pmatrix} a&b\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}$$ \n    where $a$ and $b$ are real numbers. We are told that $a=1$, and need to determine $b$. If $\\Nul A$ is the line $x_1=-2x_2$ then $\\begin{pmatrix}-2\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ is in the null space and $$\\begin{pmatrix} 1&b\\\\0&0 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}-2\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}$$ So $-2+b=0$, or $b=2$. So we must set $$a_1=1, a_2 = 2, a_3 =0, a_4=0$$ There no are other choices for $a_1, a_2$ and we must have that $a_3=a_4=0$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If matrix $A$ is $2\\times2$, $\\Col A$ is the line $x_2 =0$ and $\\Null A$ is the line $x_1=-4x_2$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} 1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where \n        $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, \n        $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If the column space is the $x_1$-axis then matrix has the form $$A= \\begin{pmatrix} a&b\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}$$ \n    where $a$ and $b$ are real numbers. If $\\Nul A$ is the line $x_1=-4x_2$ then $\\begin{pmatrix}-4\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ is in the null space and $$\\begin{pmatrix} a&b\\\\0&0 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}-4\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}$$ So $-4a+b=0$, and we can choose $a=1$ and $b=4$. So we can set $$a_1=1, \\ a_2 = 4,\\  a_3 =0, \\ \\textbf{}a_4=0$$ We are told that $a_1 = 1$ so this is the only possible answer. \n    } \n   \\else"
            }
        ],
        "Q6a.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose that we want reflect points in $\\mathbb R^2$ across the line $x_1 = 4$. Using homogeneous coordinates we can use a transform of the form $T(\\vec x) = A\\vec x$, where $\\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^3$ and $A$ is $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_1\\\\0&1&a_2\\\\0&0&a_3\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}b_1&b_2&0\\\\b_3&b_4&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&c_1\\\\0&1&c_2\\\\0&0&c_3 \\end{pmatrix}$$ Then $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The matrices we need are\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&4\\\\0&1&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}-1&0&0\\\\0&1&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&-4\\\\0&1&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}$$    \nSo $a_1 = 4, a_2 = 0, b_1 = -1, b_2 = 0, c_1 = -4, c_2 = 0$. \n}"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&4\\\\2&5\\end{pmatrix}$ and $A^{-1} = \\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix}$. Then $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "We can either use the formula for the inverse of a $2\\times 2 $ matrix or row reduce the block matrix $\\begin{pmatrix} A & I\\end{pmatrix}$. The latter yields\n    \\begin{align}\n        \\begin{pmatrix} A & I\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&4&1&0\\\\2&5&0&1\\end{pmatrix} \n        \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 1&2&1/2&0\\\\0&1&-1&1\\end{pmatrix}\n        \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&5/2&-2\\\\0&1&-1&1\\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    Thus $A^{-1} =\\begin{pmatrix} 5/2&-2\\\\-1&1\\end{pmatrix}$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "%%% NUMBERS MORE MESSY THAN NECESSARY %%%\n    \\part Suppose $A$ has the LU factorization $A=LU$, where $L = \\begin{pmatrix} 1 & 0 \\\\ 4 & 1 \\end{pmatrix}$ and $U = \\begin{pmatrix} 2 & 5 \\\\ 0 & 4 \\end{pmatrix}$. Then the system $Ax=b$ where $b = \\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\3 \\end{pmatrix}$ can be solved using $Ly=b$ and $Ux=y$, with $y = \\begin{pmatrix} y_1\\\\y_2\\end{pmatrix}$ and $x= \\begin{pmatrix} x_1\\\\x_2\\end{pmatrix}$. Then $y_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $y_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $x_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $x_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.\n\n    %%% NUMBERS MORE MESSY THAN NECESSARY %%%",
                "answer": "We can solve $Ly=b$ by row reducing the augmented matrix $( L \\, | \\, b)$.\n    $$\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&2\\\\4&1&3\\end{pmatrix} \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&2\\\\0&1&-5\\end{pmatrix}$$\n    Thus $y = \\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\-5\\end{pmatrix}$. Solve $Ux=y$ by row reducing the augmented matrix $(U \\, | \\ y)$. \n    $$\\begin{pmatrix} 2&5&2\\\\0&4&-5\\end{pmatrix} \n    \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 2&5&2\\\\0&1&-5/4\\end{pmatrix}\n    \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 2&0&8/4+25/4\\\\0&1&-5/4\\end{pmatrix}\n    \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&33/8\\\\0&1&-5/4\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    Thus $y_1=2, y_2=-5, x_1=33/8, x_2 = -5/4$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If the consumption matrix for an economy is $C=\\frac{1}{10}\\begin{pmatrix} 2&0\\\\4&9\\end{pmatrix}$ then the output $x$ to meet a desired output $d=\\begin{pmatrix} 16\\\\20\\end{pmatrix}$ is $x=\\begin{pmatrix} x_1\\\\x_2 \\end{pmatrix}$, where $x_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $x_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The output we need satisfies \n$$x = d + Cx$$\nWhich is also\n$$(I-C)x = d$$\nBut \n$$I-C = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1\\end{pmatrix} - \\begin{pmatrix} 0.2 & 0 \\\\ 0.4 & 0.9 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0.8 & 0 \\\\ -0.4 & 0.1 \\end{pmatrix}$$\nThus we can determine $x$ by reducing the augmented matrix below as follows. \n\\begin{align}\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0.8 & 0 & 16\\\\ -0.4 &  0.1 & 20\\end{pmatrix} \n    & \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 8 & 0 & 160\\\\ -4 & 1 & 200\\end{pmatrix} \n     \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 1 & 0 & 20\\\\ -4 & 1 & 200\\end{pmatrix} \n     \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 1 & 0 & 20\\\\ 0 & 1 & 280\\end{pmatrix} \n\\end{align}\nThus $x_1 = 20$, $x_2 = 280$. \n}"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose we want to project points in $\\mathbb R^2$ onto the line $x_2=4$. Using homogeneous coordinates we can use a transform of the form $T(\\vec x) = A\\vec x$, where $A$ is $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_1\\\\0&1&a_2\\\\0&0&a_3\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}b_1&b_2&0\\\\b_3&b_4&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&c_1\\\\0&1&c_2\\\\0&0&c_3 \\end{pmatrix}$$\nThen $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The matrices we need are\n$$A = \n\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&4\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&0&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\n\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&-4\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\n$$    \nSo $a_1 = 0, a_2 = 4, b_1 = 1, b_2 = 0, c_1 = 0, c_2 = -4$. \n}"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose that we want reflect points in $\\mathbb R^2$ across the line $x_2 = 4$. Using homogeneous coordinates we can use a transform of the form $T(\\vec x) = A\\vec x$, where $\\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^3$ and $A$ is $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_1\\\\0&1&a_2\\\\0&0&a_3\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}b_1&b_2&0\\\\b_3&b_4&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&c_1\\\\0&1&c_2\\\\0&0&c_3 \\end{pmatrix}$$ Then $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The matrices we need are\n    $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&4\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}1&0&0\\\\0&-1&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&-4\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}$$    \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If the Leontief production equation for an economy with two sectors has consumption matrix $C=\\begin{pmatrix}0.4&0\\\\0.1&0.2 \\end{pmatrix}$ and demand vector $\\vec d=\\begin{pmatrix} 60\\\\6\\end{pmatrix}$ then the production vector has the form $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} x_1 \\\\ x_2 \\end{pmatrix}$ where $x_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$ and $x_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The production model is $$x = d + Cx$$ Rearranging yields $$(I-C)x = d$$ And $I-C$ is\n    \\begin{align}\n        I -  C = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1 \\end{pmatrix} - \\begin{pmatrix} .4&0\\\\.1&.2\\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} .6&0\\\\-0.1&.8\\end{pmatrix} \n    \\end{align} \n    Expressing $(I-C)x=d$ as an augmented matrix and reducing gives the solution. \n    \\begin{align}\n        \\begin{pmatrix} .6&0&60\\\\-0.1&.8&6\\end{pmatrix} \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 6&0&600\\\\-1&8&60\\end{pmatrix}\\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&100\\\\-1&8&60\\end{pmatrix}\\sim\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&100\\\\0&1&20\\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    Therefore $x_1=100$, $x_2 = 20$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ has LU factorization $A=LU$, where $U = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&0\\\\0&3\\end{pmatrix}$, and the solution to $L\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix}6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$ is $\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} -2\\\\27 \\end{pmatrix}$, then the solution to $A\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix}6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$ is $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} x_1\\\\x_2\\end{pmatrix}$, where $x_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $x_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.\n    %",
                "answer": "If $A\\vec x = LU\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$, and $L\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} 6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$ then $U\\vec x = \\vec y$. But we are given $\\vec y$, so \\begin{align} U\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} -2\\\\27 \\end{pmatrix}\\end{align} Expressing this as an augmented matrix we obtain \n    $$\\begin{pmatrix} 2&0 & -2\\\\0&3&27 \\end{pmatrix}$$\n    Thus $x_1 = -1$, $x_2= 27/3 = 9$. \n    } \n    \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose we want to use homogeneous coordinates to rotate points in $\\mathbb R^2$ counter-clockwise by $\\pi/2$ radians about the point $(-1,2)$. We can use a transform of the form $T(\\vec x) = A\\vec x$, where $A$ is $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_1\\\\0&1&a_2\\\\0&0&a_3\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}b_1&b_2&0\\\\b_3&b_4&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&c_1\\\\0&1&c_2\\\\0&0&c_3 \\end{pmatrix}$$\nThen $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The matrices we need are\n$$A = \n\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&-1\\\\0&1&2\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n\\begin{pmatrix} 0&1&0\\\\-1&0&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\n\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&-2\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\n$$    \nSo $a_1 = 1, a_2 = 0, b_1 = 0, b_2 = 1, c_1 = 1, c_2 = 0$. \n}"
            },
            {
                "question": "0\n\n\\part Suppose we want to use homogeneous coordinates to rotate points in $\\mathbb R^2$ clockwise by $\\pi/2$ radians about the point $(2,1)$. We can use a transform of the form $T(\\vec x) = A\\vec x$, where $A$ is $$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&a_1\\\\0&1&a_2\\\\0&0&a_3\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix}b_1&b_2&0\\\\b_3&b_4&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&c_1\\\\0&1&c_2\\\\0&0&c_3 \\end{pmatrix}$$\nThen $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $b_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $c_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The matrices we need are\n$$A = \n\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&2\\\\0&1&1\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n\\begin{pmatrix} 0&1&0\\\\-1&0&0\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\n\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&-2\\\\0&1&-1\\\\0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}\n$$    \nSo $a_1 = 2, a_2 = 1, b_1 = 0, b_2 = 1, c_1 = -2, c_2 = -1$. \n}"
            },
            {
                "question": "1\n\\part If the LU factorization is $A=LU$, where $U$ is obtained by applying one row operation to $A$, and $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1&2&1\\\\8&20&50\\end{pmatrix}$. Then $L = \\begin{pmatrix} 1& 0\\\\l_1 & 1 \\end{pmatrix} $ and $U= \\begin{pmatrix} 1&2 & 4\\\\u_1 & u_2 & u_3 \\end{pmatrix}$, where $l_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$, $u_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$, $u_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$ and $u_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$.",
                "answer": "To reduce $A$ to $U$ we need exactly one row operation, $R_2 - 8R_1 \\to R_2$. That row operation applied to $A$ gives us NEED TO FIX THIS PART $$ U = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&3\\\\0&3\\end{pmatrix}$$. So $u_1 = 2, u_2 = 3, u_3=0, u_4 = 3$. \n}"
            },
            {
                "question": "2\n\n\\part If $A$ has LU factorization $A=LU$, where $U = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&1\\\\0&3\\end{pmatrix}$, and the solution to $L\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix}6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$ is $\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\24 \\end{pmatrix}$, then the solution to $A\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix}6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$ is $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} x_1\\\\x_2\\end{pmatrix}$, where $x_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $x_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $A\\vec x = LU\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$, and $L\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} 6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$ then $U\\vec x = \\vec y$. But we are given $\\vec y$, so \\begin{align} U\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\24 \\end{pmatrix}\\end{align} Expressing this as an augmented matrix we obtain \n$$\\begin{pmatrix} 2&0 & 2\\\\0&3&24 \\end{pmatrix}$$\nThus $x_1 = 1$, $x_2= 24/3 = 8$. \n} \n\\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "3\n\\part If $A$ has LU factorization $A=LU$, where $U = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&0\\\\0&3\\end{pmatrix}$, and the solution to $L\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix}6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$ is $\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\24 \\end{pmatrix}$, then the solution to $A\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix}6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$ is $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} x_1\\\\x_2\\end{pmatrix}$, where $x_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $x_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $A\\vec x = LU\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$, and $L\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} 6\\\\12 \\end{pmatrix}$ then $U\\vec x = \\vec y$. But we are given $\\vec y$, so \\begin{align} U\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\24 \\end{pmatrix}\\end{align} Expressing this as an augmented matrix we obtain \n$$\\begin{pmatrix} 2&0 & 2\\\\0&3&24 \\end{pmatrix}$$\nThus $x_1 = 1$, $x_2= 24/3 = 8$. \n} \n\\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "4\n\\part If $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&3\\\\4&9 \\end{pmatrix}$ has the LU factorization $A=LU$, where $L = \\begin{pmatrix} 1 & 0 \\\\ l_1 & 1 \\end{pmatrix}$ and $U = \\begin{pmatrix} u_1 & u_2 \\\\ u_3 & u_4 \\end{pmatrix}$, then $l_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $u_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $u_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $u_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$,$u_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "To reduce $A$ to $U$ we need exactly one row operation, $R_2 - 2R_1 \\to R_2$. That row operation applied to $A$ gives us $$ U = \\begin{pmatrix} 2&3\\\\0&3\\end{pmatrix}$$. So $u_1 = 2, u_2 = 3, u_3=0, u_4 = 3$. \n}"
            }
        ],
        "Q6h.tex": [],
        "Q6g.tex": [],
        "Q6f.tex": [],
        "Q6b.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part $A\\!= \\! \\begin{pmatrix} 2&6\\\\2&6\\end{pmatrix}$ is row equivalent to $E\\!=\\!\\begin{pmatrix} 1&3\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}$. A basis for $\\Col A$ is $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\k \\end{pmatrix}$, where $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.8cm}}$.",
                "answer": "We are given the vector $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\k\\end{pmatrix}$ which is a basis for $\\Col A$ for $k=1$, because every column is in the span of $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$.\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose $A$, $B$, and $C$ are $2\\times2$ matrices, $A = BC$, and $\\Null B$ is the line $x_1=0$. If $T(\\vec x)=C\\vec x$ rotates vectors clockwise by $\\pi/2$ radians about the origin, then $\\Null A$ is spanned by $\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} y_1\\\\y_2\\end{pmatrix}$ where $y_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $y_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$. Please use numbers for $y_1$ and $y_2$ (not variables).",
                "answer": "Note that the line $x_1=0$ is the $x_2$-axis, and that there are a few ways to approach this problem. Here are two different methods. \n    \\begin{itemize}\n        \\item \\textbf{Method 1}: The transform $T(x) = Ax = BCx$ first rotates vectors clockwise by $\\pi/2$ radians about the origin. Any vector on the $x_1$-axis gets rotated to the $x_2$-axis. Vectors on the $x_1$-axis are in the span of $y = \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}$. So any vector in the span of $y$ is rotated into $\\Null B$, so $BCy = 0$. But $A=BC$ so $\\Null A$ is spanned by $y = \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}$. We can choose $y_1 = 1$ and $y_2=0$. \n        \\item \\textbf{Method 2}: The transform $T(x) = Ax = BCx$ first rotates vectors clockwise by $\\pi/2$ radians about the origin. In other words, $C$ will transform $e_1 = \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}$ to $T_C(e_1) = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix}$, and $e_2 = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\ 1 \\end{pmatrix}$ to $T_C(e_2) = \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}$. This means that the standard matrix of the transform $T_C$ is $C = \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1\\\\-1&0\\end{pmatrix}$, and $C$ will transform a vector of the form $\\begin{pmatrix}x_1\\\\x_2 \\end{pmatrix}$ to $\\begin{pmatrix} x_2 \\\\ -x_1\\end{pmatrix}$. But $\\Null B$ is the line spanned by $\\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$, so $T_C(x)$ is in $\\Null B$ when $x_2 = 0$. So $y = \\begin{pmatrix} x_1 \\\\ x_2 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix}x_1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}$. So we can choose $y_1 = 1$ and $y_2 = 0$. \n    \\end{itemize}\n    Do not leave your answer as $y_1 = x_1$ and $y_2=0$ because then you haven't specified that $x_1 \\ne 0$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part A basis for the subspace $S = \\{ \\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^2 \\, | \\, x_1=3x_2 \\}$ is $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} k\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$, where $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.8cm}}$.",
                "answer": "We are given the vector $\\begin{pmatrix} k\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ which is in $S$ for $k=3$, and $\\Dim S = 1$ so $\\begin{pmatrix} 3\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ is a basis for $S$.\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose $A$, $B$, and $C$ are $2\\times2$ matrices, $A = BC$, and $\\Null B$ is the line $x_2=0$. If $T(\\vec x)=C\\vec x$ reflects vectors through the line $x_1+x_2= 0$, then $\\Null A$ is spanned by the vector $\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} y_1\\\\y_2\\end{pmatrix}$ where $y_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $y_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "We seek the vectors that are mapped by $T$ onto the null space of $B$. We know that $T$ is a reflection through the line $x_2=-x_1$, so $T$ maps vectors of the form $v = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\ k \\end{pmatrix}$ onto the $x_1$-axis (which is the line $x_2=0$). In other words, \n    $$Cv = C \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\k\\end{pmatrix}$$\n    will be a point on the $x_1$-axis. Then\n    $$Av = BCv=B(Cv)$$\n    will be a zero vector, because $Cv$ is in the null space of $B$. So a basis for the null space of $A$ is $v = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\ 1 \\end{pmatrix}$. Because any vector in the span of $v$ satisfies $Av = BCv = 0$. \n    \n    Note that there are other valid approaches to this problem. We could also construct both matrices $B$ and $C$, compute their product which is $A$, and then determine a basis for the null space of $A$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part A basis for the subspace $S = \\{ \\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^2 \\, | \\, x_1=3x_2 \\}$ is $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} k\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$, where $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.8cm}}$.",
                "answer": "We are given the vector $\\begin{pmatrix} k\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ which is in $S$ for $k=3$, and $\\Dim S = 1$ so $\\begin{pmatrix} 3\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ is a basis for $S$. The only correct answer to this question is $k=3$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part $A\\!= \\! \\begin{pmatrix} 2&6\\\\2&6\\end{pmatrix}$ is row equivalent to $E\\!=\\!\\begin{pmatrix} 1&3\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}$. A basis for $\\Col A$ is $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\k \\end{pmatrix}$, where $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.8cm}}$.",
                "answer": "We are given the vector $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\k\\end{pmatrix}$ which is a basis for $\\Col A$ for $k=1$, because every column is in the span of $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$.\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose $A$, $B$, and $C$ are $2\\times2$ matrices, $A = BC$, and $\\Null B$ is the line $x_1=0$. If $T(\\vec x)=C\\vec x$ reflects vectors through the line $x_1+x_2= 0$, then $\\Null A$ is spanned by the vector $\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} y_1\\\\y_2\\end{pmatrix}$ where $y_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $y_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$. Please use numbers for $y_1$ and $y_2$ (not variables).",
                "answer": "Any vector in the span of $v = \\begin{pmatrix} k\\\\0\\end{pmatrix}$, where $k \\ne 0$ will be reflected by $C$ onto the $x_2$ axis where $x_1 = 0$. That is, if $y$ is in the span of $v$, then $BCy = 0$. So $y_1$ can be any non-zero number, and $y_2 = 0$. We can choose $y_1 = 1$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part $A\\!= \\! \\begin{pmatrix} 1&4\\\\2&8\\end{pmatrix}$ is row equivalent to $E\\!=\\!\\begin{pmatrix} 1&2\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}$. A basis for $\\Col A$ is $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\k \\end{pmatrix}$, where $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.8cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The columns of $A$ are spanned by $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\2\\end{pmatrix}$, \n    so $k=2$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part A basis for the subspace $S = \\{ \\vec x \\in \\mathbb R^2 \\, | \\, x_1=2x_2 \\}$ is $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix} k & 1 \\end{pmatrix}^T$, where $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{0.8cm}}$.",
                "answer": "We are given the vector $\\begin{pmatrix} k\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ which is in $S$ for $k=2$, and $\\Dim S = 1$ so $\\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ is a basis for $S$.\n    }"
            }
        ],
        "Q6i.tex": []
    },
    "Exam3": {
        "Exam2Q2.tex": [],
        "Exam2Q6.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\question[2] If $x \\in \\mathbb R^2$ and $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 5&-5\\\\5&5\\end{pmatrix}$ then the transform $x \\to Ax$ is the composition of a rotation and a scaling. Determine the angle of the rotation $\\phi$ and the scale factor $r$. Assume that $\\phi$ measures angles counter-clockwise from the $x_1$-axis. Please show your work.",
                "answer": "By inspection $A$ is a rotation-dilation matrix and therefore its eigenvalues are $\\lambda = a \\pm bi = 5 \\pm 5i$.\n    The scale factor is the distance $r = \\sqrt{a^2 + b^2} = \\sqrt{5^2 + 5^2} = 5\\sqrt 2$, and the angle of rotation is $\\tan^{-1} (b/a) = \\pi/4$. \n    \n    A few notes regarding the solution to this problem: \n    \\begin{itemize}\n        \\item This is a \\textit{show your work} question, so do write down some of your intermediate steps. \n        \\item It isn't necessary to construct the characteristic polynomial and determine its roots to obtain these eigenvalues in this case, because the matrix $A$ is a rotation-dilation matrix. $2\\times 2$ rotation dilation matrices always have $a\\pm ib$ as their eigenvalues. For other problems where you need to compute eigenvalues, you should show some intermediate steps when computing eigenvalues. \n        \\item One way to check whether your calculations for $r$ and $\\phi$ are correct is to compute the output of the transform $x \\ to Ax$ for a sample point. For example $Ae_1 = \\begin{pmatrix} 5&-5\\\\5&5\\end{pmatrix}\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix}5\\\\5 \\end{pmatrix}$, which corresponds to the point $(5,5)$. The distance from the origin to this point is $5\\sqrt2$ and the input point was rotated by $\\pi/4$ radians counterclockwise to where it ended up after the transform. \n        \\item It is ok to leave your answer for $\\phi$ as $\\phi = \\tan^{-1} 1$. \n        \\item If you would like to get more practice on a question like this, exercises from section 5.5 of our textbook are recommended. They might be in the MML Study Plan. \n    \\end{itemize}\n     \n    \n    \n\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\question[2] Calculate the steady state for the Markov chain shown below. Please show your work.  \n        \\begin{center}\n        \\begin{tikzpicture}[->,>=stealth',shorten >=1pt,auto,node distance=3cm,thick]\n        \\tikzstyle{every state}=[circle,fill=gray!10,draw,thick,,font=\\bf, line width=0.4mm]\n    \n        \\node[state] (A) {A};\n        \\node[state]  (B) [right of=A] {B};\n        \\path \n            (A) edge    [bend left] node {0.3} (B)\n                edge    [loop left] node {0.7} (A)\n            (B) edge    [loop right] node {0.4} (B) \n                edge    [bend left] node {0.6} (A);\n        \\end{tikzpicture} \n        \\end{center}",
                "answer": "\\begin{align}\n            P-I &= \\frac{1}{10} \\begin{pmatrix} 7 & 6 \\\\ 3 & 4\\end{pmatrix} - \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1 \\end{pmatrix} = \\frac{1}{10}\\begin{pmatrix}-3&6\\\\3&-6 \\end{pmatrix} \\sim \\begin{pmatrix}-1&2\\\\0&0 \\end{pmatrix}\n        \\end{align}\n        The steady-state is: \n        $$ \\vec q = \\frac{1}{3}\\begin{pmatrix}2\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$$\n        }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\question[2] Calculate the steady state for the Markov chain shown below. Please show your work.  \n        \\begin{center}\n        \\begin{tikzpicture}[->,>=stealth',shorten >=1pt,auto,node distance=3cm,thick]\n        \\tikzstyle{every state}=[circle,fill=gray!10,draw,thick,,font=\\bf, line width=0.4mm]\n    \n        \\node[state] (A) {A};\n        \\node[state]  (B) [right of=A] {B};\n        \\path \n            (A) edge    [bend left] node {0.3} (B)\n                edge    [loop left] node {0.7} (A)\n            (B) edge    [loop right] node {0.8} (B) \n                edge    [bend left] node {0.2} (A);\n        \\end{tikzpicture} \n        \\end{center}",
                "answer": "\\begin{align}\n            P-I &= \\frac{1}{10} \\begin{pmatrix} 7 & 2 \\\\ 3 & 8\\end{pmatrix} - \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1 \\end{pmatrix} = \\frac{1}{10}\\begin{pmatrix}-3&2\\\\3&-2 \\end{pmatrix} \\sim \\begin{pmatrix}-3&2\\\\0&0 \\end{pmatrix}\n        \\end{align}\n        The steady-state is: \n        $$ \\vec q = \\frac{1}{5}\\begin{pmatrix}2\\\\3 \\end{pmatrix}$$\n        } \n    \\else\n    \\vfill"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\question[2] Calculate the steady state for the Markov chain shown below. Please show your work.  \n        \\begin{center}\n        \\begin{tikzpicture}[->,>=stealth',shorten >=1pt,auto,node distance=3cm,thick]\n        \\tikzstyle{every state}=[circle,fill=gray!10,draw,thick,,font=\\bf, line width=0.4mm]\n    \n        \\node[state] (A) {A};\n        \\node[state]  (B) [right of=A] {B};\n        \\path \n            (A) edge    [bend left] node {0.3} (B)\n                edge    [loop left] node {0.7} (A)\n            (B) edge    [loop right] node {0.8} (B) \n                edge    [bend left] node {0.2} (A);\n        \\end{tikzpicture} \n        \\end{center}",
                "answer": "\\begin{align}\n            P-I &= \\frac{1}{10} \\begin{pmatrix} 7 & 2 \\\\ 3 & 8\\end{pmatrix} - \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1 \\end{pmatrix} = \\frac{1}{10}\\begin{pmatrix}-3&2\\\\3&-2 \\end{pmatrix} \\sim \\begin{pmatrix}-3&2\\\\0&0 \\end{pmatrix}\n        \\end{align}\n        The steady-state is: \n        $$ \\vec q = \\frac{1}{5}\\begin{pmatrix}2\\\\3 \\end{pmatrix}$$\n        }"
            },
            {
                "question": "2 % NOT NEEDED? \n    \\question[2] Calculate the steady state for the Markov chain shown below. Please show your work.  \n        \\begin{center}\n        \\begin{tikzpicture}[->,>=stealth',shorten >=1pt,auto,node distance=3cm,thick]\n        \\tikzstyle{every state}=[circle,fill=gray!10,draw,thick,,font=\\bf, line width=0.4mm]\n    \n        \\node[state] (A) {A};\n        \\node[state]  (B) [right of=A] {B};\n        \\path \n            (A) edge    [bend left] node {0.3} (B)\n                edge    [loop left] node {0.7} (A)\n            (B) edge    [loop right] node {0.4} (B) \n                edge    [bend left] node {0.6} (A);\n        \\end{tikzpicture} \n        \\end{center}",
                "answer": "Find the probability vector in the kernel of $P_I$. \n        \\begin{align}\n            P-I &= \\frac{1}{10} \\begin{pmatrix} 7 & 6 \\\\ 3 & 4\\end{pmatrix} - \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1 \\end{pmatrix} = \\frac{1}{10}\\begin{pmatrix}-3&6\\\\3&-6 \\end{pmatrix} \\sim \\begin{pmatrix}-1&2\\\\0&0 \\end{pmatrix}\n        \\end{align}\n        The steady-state is: \n        $$ \\vec q = \\frac{1}{3}\\begin{pmatrix}2\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$$\n        } \n    \\else \n        \\vfill"
            },
            {
                "question": "3 % NOT NEEDED? \n    \\question[2] Calculate the steady state for the Markov chain shown below. Please show your work.  \n        \\begin{center}\n        \\begin{tikzpicture}[->,>=stealth',shorten >=1pt,auto,node distance=3cm,thick]\n        \\tikzstyle{every state}=[circle,fill=gray!10,draw,thick,,font=\\bf, line width=0.4mm]\n    \n        \\node[state] (A) {A};\n        \\node[state]  (B) [right of=A] {B};\n        \\path \n            (A) edge    [bend left] node {0.2} (B)\n                edge    [loop left] node {0.8} (A)\n            (B) edge    [loop right] node {0.4} (B) \n                edge    [bend left] node {0.6} (A);\n        \\end{tikzpicture} \n        \\end{center}",
                "answer": "The steady state has eigenvalue 1. So it is the probability vector in the null space (i.e. - the kernel) of $P-I$. \n        \\begin{align} \n            P-I &= \\frac{1}{10} \\begin{pmatrix} 8 & 6 \\\\ 2 & 4\\end{pmatrix} - \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1 \\end{pmatrix} = \\frac{1}{10}\\begin{pmatrix}-2&6\\\\2&-6 \\end{pmatrix} \\sim \\begin{pmatrix}-1&3\\\\0&0 \\end{pmatrix}\n        \\end{align}\n        The steady-state is: \n        $$ \\vec q = \\frac{1}{4}\\begin{pmatrix}3\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$$\n        }"
            }
        ],
        "Exam2Q3.tex": [],
        "Exam2Q8.tex": [],
        "Exam2Q5.tex": []
    },
    "Exam1": {
        "Q3FITBa.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first reflects points in $\\mathbb R^2$ through the line $x_1 + x_2 = 0$ and then projects them onto the $x_2$-axis then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, the first standard vector $e_1$ is transformed as follows.\n    \\begin{align}\n        e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix} \n    \\end{align}\n    In other words, the reflection maps $e_1 = \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}$ to $\\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix}$, and the projection does not affect the vector because it is already on the $x_2$-axis. \n\n    The second standard vector $e_2$ is transformed as follows. \n    \\begin{align}\n        e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \n    \\end{align}\n    In other words, the reflection maps $e_2 = \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}$ to $\\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}$, and the projection collapses vector onto the $x_2$-axis, turning it into a zero vector. \n\n    Putting everything together we have\n    \\begin{align}\n        e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix} = T(e_1)\\\\\n        e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} = T(e_2)\n    \\end{align}        \n    Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & 0\\\\-1 & 0\\end{pmatrix}$, so $a_1=0$, $a_2=0$, $a_3=-1$, $a_4=0$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first rotates points in $\\mathbb R^2$ counter-clockwise about the origin by $\\pi/2$ radians and then reflects them through the line $x_1 = 0$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, we obtain\n        \\begin{align}\n            e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\\\\n            e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n        \\end{align}\n        Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & 1\\\\1 & 0\\end{pmatrix}$, so $a_1=0$, $a_2=1$, $a_3=1$, $a_4=0$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first rotates points in $\\mathbb R^2$ clockwise about the origin by $\\pi/2$ radians and then reflects them through the line $x_2 = x_1$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, we obtain\n        \\begin{align}\n            e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \n            \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \n               \\begin{pmatrix}-1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\\\\n            e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n            \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \n        \\end{align}\n        Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix}-1 & 0\\\\ 0 & 1\\end{pmatrix}$. So $a_1=-1$, $a_2=0$, $a_3=0$, $a_4=1$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first rotates points clockwise in $\\mathbb R^2$ about the origin by $\\pi/2$ radians and then reflects them through the line $x_2 = 0$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, we obtain\n    \\begin{align}\n        e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\\\\n        e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix} = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & 1\\\\1 & 0\\end{pmatrix}$, so $a_1=0$, $a_2=1$, $a_3=1$, $a_4=0$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first rotates points in $\\mathbb R^2$ clockwise about the origin by $3\\pi/2$ radians and then reflects them through the line $x_1 = x_2$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, we obtain\n    \\begin{align}\n        e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}\\to \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\\\\n        e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 1 & 0\\\\0 & -1 \\end{pmatrix}$, so $a_1=1$, $a_2=0$, $a_3=0$, $a_4=-1$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first reflects points in $\\mathbb R^2$ through the line $x_1 + x_2 = 0$, and then projects them onto the $x_1$-axis, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, we obtain\n    \\begin{align}\n        e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\\\\n        e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & -1\\\\0 & 0\\end{pmatrix}$, so $a_1=0$, $a_2=-1$, $a_3=0$, $a_4=0$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first reflects points in $\\mathbb R^2$ through the line $x_1 + x_2 = 0$, and then projects them onto the $x_2$-axis, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, we obtain\n    \\begin{align}\n        e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix} \\\\\n        e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & 0\\\\-1 & 0\\end{pmatrix}$, so $a_1=0$, $a_2=0$, $a_3=-1$, $a_4=0$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first projects points in $\\mathbb R^2$ onto the $x_2$-axis, then rotates them by $\\pi/2$ radians counterclockwise about the origin, $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, we obtain\n    \\begin{align}\n        e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\\\\n        e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} -1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & -1\\\\0 & 0\\end{pmatrix}$, so $a_1=0$, $a_2=-1$, $a_3=0$, $a_4=0$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first reflects points in $\\mathbb R^2$ through the line $x_1 = 0$, and then rotates them by $\\pi/2$ radians clockwise about the origin, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, we obtain\n    \\begin{align}\n        e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}-1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\\\\n        e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & 1\\\\1 & 0\\end{pmatrix}$, so $a_1=0$, $a_2=1$, $a_3=1$, $a_4=0$. \n    \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "0\n    \\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first rotates points in $\\mathbb R^2$ clockwise about the origin by $3\\pi/2$ radians and then reflects them through the line $x_1 = 0$, then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Track the path of the standard basis elements. \n     \\begin{align}\n         e_1 &\\to  \\begin{pmatrix} -1 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix}  \\to \n         \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\ 1  \\end{pmatrix}\n         \\\\ \n         e_2 &\\to \\begin{pmatrix} 1 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix} \n         \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 1 \\\\ 0 \\end{pmatrix} \n     \\end{align}\n    So the matrix $A = \\begin{pmatrix}\n        0 & 1 \\\\ 1 & 0 \n    \\end{pmatrix}$\n        } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "1\n    \\part If $A$ is $2 \\times 2$ and $T_A(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ is a linear transform that first  reflects them through the line $x_1 = x_2$, and then rotates points in $\\mathbb R^2$ clockwise about the origin by $\\pi$ radians,then $A=\\begin{pmatrix} a_1 & a_2 \\\\ a_3 & a_4 \\end{pmatrix} $ where $a_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$, $a_3 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$ and $a_4 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using $A = \\begin{pmatrix} T(e_1) & T(e_2) \\end{pmatrix}$, we obtain\n    \\begin{align}\n        e_1 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\1 \\end{pmatrix}\\to \\begin{pmatrix}0\\\\-1 \\end{pmatrix} \n        \\\\\n        e_2 &= \\begin{pmatrix} 0 \\\\1 \\end{pmatrix} \\to \\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\\to \\begin{pmatrix}-1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}\n    \\end{align}\n    Thus $A = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & -1\\\\-1 & 0 \\end{pmatrix}$, so $a_1=0$, $a_2=-1$, $a_3=-1$, $a_4=0$.  \n    } \n   \\else"
            }
        ],
        "Q3FITBd.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $3\\times 7$ and $Ax=b$ is consistent for all $b \\in \\mathbb R^3$, how many pivots does $A$ have? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}",
                "answer": "There must be a pivot in every row of $A$ so there are 3 pivots. \n\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is a $3\\times7$ matrix, $b \\in \\mathbb R^3$ is in the span of the columns of $A$, $x \\in \\mathbb R^7$, and $A$ has exactly $2$ pivots, then how many free variables does $Ax=b$ have? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "There are $7$ columns and $2$ pivots, so there must be 5 free variables. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $5\\times 7$ and $\\vec x \\to A\\vec x$ is onto, how many pivots does $A$ have? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "There are $5$ rows and very row must be pivotal, so there must be 5 pivots. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part A is $12\\times 7$ and $\\vec x \\to A\\vec x$ is one-to-one. How many pivots does $A$ have? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "Every column must be pivotal, so the answer is 7. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Matrix $A$ is $12\\times 7$ and $\\vec x \\to A\\vec x$ is one-to-one. How many pivots does $A$ have? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "There are 7 columns and if the transform is one-to-one there must be a pivot in every column, so there are 7 pivots. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A =  \\begin{pmatrix}k & k\\\\2&2 \\end{pmatrix}$, then   $v=\\begin{pmatrix} 4\\\\1\\end{pmatrix}$ is in the span of the columns of $A$ when $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "We need $k=8$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is a $3\\times8$ matrix, $b \\in \\mathbb R^3$ is in the span of the columns of $A$,  $A$ has exactly $2$ pivots, and $x \\in \\mathbb R^8$,     then how many free variables does $Ax=b$ have? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "Since $A$ has 2 pivots, it has 6 free variables. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is a $3\\times8$ matrix, $b \\in \\mathbb R^3$ is in the span of the columns of $A$,  and $x \\to Ax \\in \\mathbf{R}^3$ is onto,     then how many free variables does $Ax=b$ have? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "Since $x\\to A x$ is onto, the matrix $A$ has 3 pivots and 5 free variables.\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $A$ is $4\\times 3$, and the linear system $A\\vec x = \\vec b$ is consistent, then $\\vec x$ has  $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$ entries and $\\vec b$ has $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$ entries.",
                "answer": "For $A\\vec x$ to be defined, $\\vec x$ must have 2 entries because $A$ has 2 columns. And $b$ has 4 entries because $A$ has that many rows. \n    } \n   \\else"
            }
        ],
        "Q3FITBc.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part  If the linear transform $T_A(\\vec x) = A\\vec x$, where $T_A \\ : \\ \\mathbb R^8 \\to \\mathbb R^4$, is onto, then $A$ has exactly $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$ pivots, the domain of $T_A$ is \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}, the co-domain of $T_A$ is $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$, and the range of $T_A$ is $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$.",
                "answer": "The standard matrix of the transform must be $4\\times8$. If the transform is onto, every row must be pivotal. So there are 4 pivots, the domain is $\\mathbb R^8$, the co-domain is $\\mathbb R^4$, and the range is also $\\mathbb R^4$.\n    }"
            }
        ],
        "Q3FITBf.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part The solution of the linear system $x_1+2x_2=1$, $x_1-x_2=4$ is the point $(h,k)$ where $h=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$, $k=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Expressing as an augmented matrix and row reducing yields\n$$\\begin{pmatrix}1&2&1\\\\1&-1&4 \\end{pmatrix} \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 1&2&1 \\\\ 0&-3&3\\end{pmatrix}\\sim\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&3\\\\0&1&-1\\end{pmatrix}$$\nSo $h=3, k=-1$. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The linear system whose augmented matrix is $\\begin{amatrix}{2} 1 & 1 & 1 \\\\ 2&k &1\\end{amatrix}$ is inconsistent when $k=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "By inspection, when $k=2$ the system will be inconsistent because the augmented matrix will have a row of the form $\\begin{pmatrix} 0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}$ after it is reduced to RREF. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The linear system whose augmented matrix is $\\begin{amatrix}{2} 1 & 1 & 1 \\\\ 3&k &1\\end{amatrix}$ is inconsistent when $k=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "By inspection, when $k=3$ the system will be inconsistent because the augmented matrix will have a row of the form $\\begin{pmatrix} 0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}$ after it is reduced to RREF. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The linear system whose augmented matrix is $\\begin{amatrix}{2} 1 & 1 & 1 \\\\ 4&k &1\\end{amatrix}$ is inconsistent when $k=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "By inspection, when $k=4$ the system will be inconsistent because the augmented matrix will have a row of the form $\\begin{pmatrix} 0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}$ after it is reduced to RREF. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The linear system whose augmented matrix is $\\begin{amatrix}{2} 1 & 2 & 1 \\\\ 3&k &1\\end{amatrix}$ is inconsistent when $k=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "By inspection, when $k=6$ the system will be inconsistent because the augmented matrix will have a row of the form $\\begin{pmatrix} 0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}$ after it is reduced to RREF. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The linear system $x_1+4x_2=1$, $3x_1+kx_2 = 1$, is inconsistent when $k=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "When $k=12$ the system will be inconsistent because the augmented matrix will have a row of the form $\\begin{pmatrix} 0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}$ after it is reduced to RREF. \n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The linear system whose augmented matrix is $\\begin{amatrix}{2} 1 & 2 & 1 \\\\ 6&k &1\\end{amatrix}$ is inconsistent when $k=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "To get something inconsistent, the first two columns should be multiplies of each other. That means $k=12$.\n        }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part The linear system whose augmented matrix is $\\begin{amatrix}{2} 2 & 1 & 1 \\\\ 4&k &1\\end{amatrix}$ is inconsistent when $k=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "By inspection, when $k=2$ the system will be inconsistent because the augmented matrix will have a row of the form $\\begin{pmatrix} 0&0&1 \\end{pmatrix}$ after it is reduced to RREF. \n        }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $E=\\begin{pmatrix} e_1 & e_2 \\\\ e_3 & e_4 \\end{pmatrix}$ is an elementary matrix that is also lower triangular, then $e_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$, $e_2=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$, $e_3=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$, $e_4=\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$. Please use numbers for each entry (not variables).",
                "answer": "One such elementary matrix is $E=\\begin{pmatrix} 1&0 \\\\ 1&1 \\end{pmatrix}$. But we can use any non-zero number for the lower-left entry. We could also use an elementary matrix that scales a row. \n\n    } \n   \\else"
            }
        ],
        "Q3FITBg.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part $A= \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&4\\\\0&1&26\\end{pmatrix}$ and $B=\\begin{pmatrix}1&0&4\\\\4&1&k \\end{pmatrix}$ are row equivalent when $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Applying one row operation to $B$ we find that $$B = \\begin{pmatrix}1&0&4\\\\4&1&k \\end{pmatrix} \\sim \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&4\\\\0&1&k-16\\end{pmatrix}$$\n    Comparing to $A$ we need the last entry in the second row to satisfy\n    $$\n    26 = k - 16\n    $$\n    Solving for $k$ gives us $k=42$. \n    }"
            }
        ],
        "Q3FITBb.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 2$, is in RREF, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "There are five such matrices: \n    $$\\begin{pmatrix} 0&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}\n    , \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}\n    , \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix} \n    , \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}\n    , \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 3$, is in RREF, has a pivot in every row, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}",
                "answer": "There are seven such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 2$, is in echelon form, has linearly independent columns, and every entry is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you create that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.00cm}}",
                "answer": "There are only two such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1\\\\0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 2$, is in RREF, $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}$ is a solution to $A\\vec x=\\vec 0$, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}",
                "answer": "There are two such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 2$, is in RREF, has linearly dependent columns, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "There are four such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "0\n    \\part Matrix $A$ is non-zero, $2\\times 2$, in RREF, is singular, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you make that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "You can construct 3 such matrices. \n    \\begin{equation}\n        \\begin{pmatrix}\n            1 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 0 \n        \\end{pmatrix}, \n                \\begin{pmatrix}\n            1 & 0 \\\\ 0 & 0 \n        \\end{pmatrix}, \n                        \\begin{pmatrix}\n            0 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 0 \n        \\end{pmatrix}\n            \\end{equation}\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "1\n    \\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 3$, is in RREF, has a pivot in every row, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}",
                "answer": "There are seven such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "2\n    \\part Matrix $A$ is $3\\times 2$, is in RREF, has exactly one pivot, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "There are three such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1\\\\0&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1\\\\0&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "3\n    \\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 2$, is in RREF, has linearly dependent columns, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "There are four such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "4\n    \\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 2$, is in echelon form, has linearly independent columns, and every entry is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you create that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.00cm}}",
                "answer": "There are only two such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0\\\\0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1\\\\0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "5\n    \\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 2$, is in RREF, $\\vec x = \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}$ is a solution to $A\\vec x=\\vec 0$, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}",
                "answer": "There are two such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&0\\\\0&0\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "6\n    \\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 3$, is in RREF, has a pivot in every row, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}",
                "answer": "There are seven such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "8\n    \\part Matrix $A$ is non-zero, $2\\times 2$, in RREF, does not have a pivot in every row, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you make that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}",
                "answer": "You can construct 3 such matrices. \n    \\begin{equation}\n        \\begin{pmatrix}\n            1 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 0 \n        \\end{pmatrix}, \n                \\begin{pmatrix}\n            1 & 0 \\\\ 0 & 0 \n        \\end{pmatrix}, \n                        \\begin{pmatrix}\n            0 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 0 \n        \\end{pmatrix}\n            \\end{equation}\n    }"
            },
            {
                "question": "9\n    \\part Matrix $A$ is $2\\times 3$, is in RREF, has a pivot in every row, and every entry of $A$ is either 1 or 0. How many different matrices can you construct that meet all of these criteria? \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.0cm}}",
                "answer": "There are seven such matrices: \n    $$\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&0\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&1&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&1\\\\0&1&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&0&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 1&1&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix},\n    \\begin{pmatrix} 0&1&0\\\\0&0&1\\end{pmatrix}\n    $$\n    }"
            }
        ],
        "Q3FITBe.tex": [
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose $\\vec v_1= \\begin{pmatrix}5\\\\8\\\\15 \\end{pmatrix}$, $\\vec v_2 = \\begin{pmatrix}2\\\\3\\\\6 \\end{pmatrix}$, and $\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} y_1\\\\y_2\\\\y_3\\end{pmatrix}$. If $A$ has 2 pivots, the transform $T(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ satisfies $T(\\vec v_1) = 2T(\\vec v_2) \\ne \\vec 0$, $y_3=3$, and $\\vec y$ satisfies $A\\vec y = \\vec 0$, then $y_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$, $y_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Using linearity: \n    \\begin{align}\n        T(\\vec v_1) &= 2T(\\vec v_2) \\\\\n        0 & = T(\\vec v_1) - 2T(\\vec v_2) \\\\\n        0 & = T(\\vec v_1 - 2\\vec v_2) \\\\\n        0 & = T\\left( \\begin{pmatrix}5\\\\8\\\\15 \\end{pmatrix}- 2 \\begin{pmatrix}2\\\\3\\\\6 \\end{pmatrix} \\right) \\\\\n        0 & = T\\left( \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\2\\\\3 \\end{pmatrix}\\right) \\\\\n        0 & = A \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\2\\\\3 \\end{pmatrix} \\\\\n        0 & = A\\vec y\n    \\end{align}\n    So $y_1 = 1$, and $y_2 = 2$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$ then the span of the columns of $A= \\begin{pmatrix} k&2\\\\3&6\\end{pmatrix}$ is a line.",
                "answer": "$k=1$\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose $\\vec v_1= \\begin{pmatrix}5\\\\2\\\\4 \\end{pmatrix}$, $\\vec v_2 = \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix}$, and $\\vec y = \\begin{pmatrix} y_1\\\\y_2\\\\y_3\\end{pmatrix}$. If $A$ has 2 pivots, the transform $T(\\vec x)=A\\vec x$ satisfies $T(\\vec v_1) = 3T(\\vec v_2) \\ne \\vec 0$, $y_3=8$, and $\\vec y$ satisfies $A\\vec y = \\vec 0$, then $y_1 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$, $y_2 = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$.",
                "answer": "Let the columns of $A$ be $a_1, a_2, a_3$. Then using linearity: \n    \\begin{align}\n        T(\\vec v_1) &= 3T(\\vec v_2) \\\\\n        0 & = T(\\vec v_1) - 3T(\\vec v_2) \\\\\n        0 & = T(\\vec v_1 - 3\\vec v_2) \\\\\n        0 & = T\\left( \\begin{pmatrix}5\\\\2\\\\4 \\end{pmatrix}- 3 \\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\1\\\\0 \\end{pmatrix} \\right) \\\\\n        0 & = T\\left( \\begin{pmatrix}2\\\\-1\\\\4 \\end{pmatrix}\\right) \\\\\n        0 & = A\\left( \\begin{pmatrix}2\\\\-1\\\\4 \\end{pmatrix}\\right) \\\\\n        0 & = 2a_1 - a_2 + 4a_3 \\\\\n        0 & = 4a_1 - 2a_2 + 8a_3 \\\\\n        0 & = A\\begin{pmatrix} 4\\\\-2\\\\8\\end{pmatrix} \n    \\end{align}\n    So $y_1 = 4$, and $y_2 = -2$. Note: if you'd like to see another example of this sort of exercise see Studio Worksheet 5 and/or the MML exercises in Section 1.8. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$ then the span of the columns of $A= \\begin{pmatrix} k&2\\\\3&6\\end{pmatrix}$ is a line.",
                "answer": "$k=1$ because then the matrix is $\\begin{pmatrix} 1&2\\\\3&6\\end{pmatrix}$. The columns are spanned by the vector $\\begin{pmatrix} 1\\\\3\\end{pmatrix}$, and the span of a single non-zero vector is a line. For any other choice of $k$ the two columns are independent, and so the span would be $\\mathbb R^2$. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Vector $b = \\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\4\\\\k\\end{pmatrix}$ is in the plane spanned by $x=\\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\0\\\\2 \\end{pmatrix}$ and $y = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\1\\\\3\\end{pmatrix}$ when $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $b$ is in the span then we can find $c_1$ and $c_2$ so that $c_1x + c_2y = b$. By inspection $c_1=2$, $c_2 = 4$, so we need $k = 2\\cdot 2 + 4\\cdot 3 = 16$. \n\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Suppose $A$ is $5\\times 8$ and every row of $A$ is pivotal. If the parametric vector form of the solutions to $A\\vec x = \\vec 0$ has the parametric vector form $\\vec x = x_2\\vec v_1 + x_4\\vec v_2 + x_6\\vec v_3$, then $\\vec v_1$  has $\\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1cm}}$ entries.",
                "answer": "The solution $\\vec x$ is a vector in $\\mathbb R^8$, so $\\vec v_1$ must also be a vector in $\\mathbb R^8$, which means it has 8 entries. \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$ then the span of the columns of $A= \\begin{pmatrix} k&2\\\\3&12\\end{pmatrix}$ is a line.",
                "answer": "The first column should be a multiple of the second. That is $k=1/2$.\n    \n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part Vector $b = \\begin{pmatrix} 2\\\\4\\\\k\\end{pmatrix}$ is in the plane spanned by $x=\\begin{pmatrix}1\\\\0\\\\2 \\end{pmatrix}$ and $y = \\begin{pmatrix} 0\\\\2\\\\3\\end{pmatrix}$ when $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$.",
                "answer": "If $b$ is in the span then we can find $c_1$ and $c_2$ so that $c_1x + c_2y = b$. By inspection $c_1=2$, $c_2 = 2$, so we need $k = 2\\cdot 2 + 2\\cdot 3 = 10$. \n\n    } \n   \\else"
            },
            {
                "question": "\\part If the span of the columns of $A = \\begin{pmatrix} k&12\\\\3&6\\end{pmatrix}$ is a line, then $k = \\framebox{\\strut\\hspace{1.25cm}}$.",
                "answer": "$k=6$\n    } \n   \\else"
            }
        ]
    }
}